<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Java on Travis Green</title>
    <link>https://greent3.github.io/tags/java/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Java on Travis Green</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://greent3.github.io/tags/java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian Deployment Triggers</title>
      <link>https://greent3.github.io/projects/contributions/deploy-triggers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greent3.github.io/projects/contributions/deploy-triggers/</guid>
      <description>Addressed pretty significant page load performance issue founde in larger deployments. Eliminates uses of intensive backend query, replacing it with an asynchronous API call against a lucene index. This change reduces page load from from 2+ minutes to nearly instant, with an incredibly responsive UI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S. Calculate My Outs (Texas Hold&#39;em)</title>
      <link>https://greent3.github.io/projects/creations/994_calculate_my_outs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greent3.github.io/projects/creations/994_calculate_my_outs/</guid>
      <description>An &amp;lsquo;out&amp;rsquo; is a card that you have yet to see and can improve your hand in Texas Hold&amp;rsquo;em. This app shuffles a deck, gives every player at the table a hand of 2 cards, deals a flop, and then uses the cards in the flop and your hand to determine which cards are necessary to increase the value of your hand.
Note: I wrote this program while quarantined in my dorm at University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T. Watch out for Old Man Herbert!</title>
      <link>https://greent3.github.io/projects/creations/995_herbert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greent3.github.io/projects/creations/995_herbert/</guid>
      <description>A playable game completed as a university project with the following specifications: The player&amp;rsquo;s health decreases when it moves
The player&amp;rsquo;s health can be rejuvinated when within proximity to items (sodas and doughnuts)
The player&amp;rsquo;s health decreaes when within proximity to enemies (old man herbert)
The game will end when the player runs out of health</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
